confused.com 2011-01-20

# Privacy Policy | Confused.com

## Confused.com takes data protection seriously

Confused.com is a trading name of Inspop.com Limited. In this Privacy Statement "we", "us" and "our" means Inspop.com Limited. Inspop.com Limited complies with and is registered under the data protection laws in the United Kingdom and takes all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal data.

We respect the privacy of every individual who visits our site and have developed this policy because we want you to feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information.

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of your information as required by law under the Data Protection Act.

Our security procedures mean that we always require proof of your identity before we will disclose information to you. Proof of identity includes your password, which is why you should never reveal it to anyone.

By using our site you are giving us permission to use your data in the ways set out in this Privacy Statement.

## Disclosure of information

In order to provide our services we need to disclose the information you entered into Confused.com to our panel of service partners, and also to their appointed representatives and to intermediaries. This information is necessary to provide you with the quotations you have requested. All personal information will be held in strictest confidence and used only for the purposes of retrieving quotes, with certain caveats as described below.

We may also use your data to review and analyse market trends and to track sales data. Where you have come to our website by clicking on a price comparison service button on another site, we will supply information about the quotations you have obtained and any policies you obtain to that site. Unless you tell them otherwise, they may contact you by post, telephone, email or SMS to promote their products and services. If you do not wish to be contacted in this way, you need to let them know by clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ button on their website.

By submitting information into our site, you are consenting for your data to be used by us and our panel of service providers, and by their appointed representatives and to intermediaries referred to in this Privacy Statement. This consent applies to both ordinary personal data and to sensitive personal data such as health information and criminal proceedings or convictions.

Before you provide us with any information about other people, you must first get their permission. This applies to all information you provide about them, but especially to sensitive data such as health information or criminal proceedings or convictions. In submitting their details, you are confirming to us that you have their permission to do so, and that they understand how their information will be used under the terms of this Privacy Statement.

We will endeavour to treat all your personal information as private and confidential. Other than under the terms of this Privacy Statement we will not disclose any of your information to anyone. We would like to bring your attention though to our obligations to disclose information in exceptional cases permitted by law. These include:

    * where we are legally compelled to do so  
    * where there is a duty to the public to disclose  
    * where disclosure is required to protect our interest  
    * where disclosure is made at your request or with your consent

If you state that your own or use a commercial vehicle, your details may be passed to Able, a company able to access a range of specialist insurance policies for the commercial vehicle market. Able insurance may telephone you directly to provide you with assistance in selecting the most suitable insurance policy for your needs from an extensive panel of policy providers. Able Insurance, whose registered office is at Ellipse Ground Floor, Padley Road, Swansea, SA1 8AN are authorised and regulated by the Financial Services Authority (authorisation number 311649 ).

## Spam (unsolicited e-mails) policy

As we don't want you to be inundated with mail from the partners, intermediaries and appointed representatives that we visit with your quote details, wherever possible our technology will automatically opt you out of receiving their marketing material. You should therefore not receive any communication from any third parties, other than outlined in this Privacy Statement. Although we cannot guarantee this, we do have contractual arrangements in place to prevent such communication, so please let us know if you do experience problems other than outlined above by emailing [communications@confused.com](mailto:communications@confused.com).

## Your rights to your personal data

If you want to know what personal information we hold about you, we will provide you with this data. If any information held is inaccurate, we will make the necessary amendments and confirm to you that these have been made. If you wish to make a request under the terms of the Data Protection Act (DPA), for the personal information we hold about you, please write to, Data Protection Manager, Inspop.com Limited, Friary House, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AE, enclosing two forms of identification displaying your name, address and/or date of birth (please send photocopies) and a cheque for the statutory administration fee of £10.00 made payable to Inspop.com Limited. We are entitled to charge you this fee under the DPA to cover our administration costs.

Inspop.com Limited, registered in England and Wales Reg. No. 03857130 at Friary House, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AE is a data controller under the DPA in relation to your personal information. The product providers and their appointed representatives and any intermediaries, will also be data controllers in relation to your personal information, and you have the same rights to know what information they hold about you as you do about the information we hold. The same applies in the case of the owners of other websites, when you have come to our site by clicking on a price comparison service button on that site. It is possible that some of these companies process personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA) (e.g. if they use overseas call centres), in which case, their websites should tell you if they do. The data protection and other laws of countries outside the EEA may not be as comprehensive as those in the UK. Any business in the UK sending personal data outside the EEA must comply with the DPA's requirements on overseas processing.

If you have any enquiry about our data protection and privacy policy or practices, please write to the Data Protection Manager, Inspop.com Limited, Friary House, Greyfriars road, Cardiff CF10 3AE.

## Help with your quotation

Many of our customers have told us that they appreciate extra information about their insurance policy from the provider who has returned the cheapest prices. For this reason by agreeing to the conditions laid out in this Privacy and Security Statement you agree that your details may be used by "us", the insurance/financial services provider or, where they are involved, their appointed representatives, or an intermediary, who provided you with the two cheapest quotes only (and in the case of a motor, home or motorbike quotation, the two cheapest quotes only before any tailoring of the cover on the results page) to contact you with a view to seeing if you are interested in purchase, highlighting any special offers or ways they might be able to help you get an even cheaper price with them. They are entitled to help you only about this particular quotation and only for a limited period of time after which they are obliged to consider your details as "off limits" i.e. opted out under the terminology of the Data Protection Act 1998. As mentioned above, it is possible that they may use an overseas call centre to do so. If you are unhappy with this condition of use then please let us know but be aware and do not submit your details to our service without first letting us know and our acknowledging your request.

In the case of our motor, home and bike insurance, although we pass your information to underlying insurance providers, (and, where they are involved, their appointed representatives and intermediaries), and they are also data controllers in respect of your data, we have contractual arrangements in place with them, limiting their use of your data in the ways described in this Privacy and Security Statement.

In the case of other insurance, and other services offered through our site, it is necessary for us to pass your information to the organisations from whom you will receive quotations you have requested from our site. While we remain data controllers in relation to that information, in connection with everything that those organisations do with that information, they will also be data controllers. Their privacy statement, setting out what they do with your personal data, will be available to you on their site. All you need to do is click on their privacy statement.

If our technology returns five or less quotes for a home or motor policy we may pass your details Call Connection Limited, who may make contact using the telephone number provided by you to access a range of specialist insurance policies which are not currently available on-line. While we remain data controllers in relation to your information, they also become a data controller and their privacy policy will apply. Call Connection Limited, whose registered office is at Saxon House, 1 Cromwell Square, Ipswich, Suffolk, 1P1 1TS are authorised and regulated by the Financial Services Authority (authorisation number 308374).

## Removal of personal information 

If you would like us to remove any personal information from our records, then please write to our Data Protection Manager at Inspop.com Limited, Friary House, Greyfriars Road, Cardiff CF10 3AE or email us at [dataprotection@confused.com](mailto:dataprotection@confused.com). We will make all reasonable efforts to delete your information from our files if it is deemed appropriate.

## Monitoring 

Monitoring or recording of your calls, emails, text messages and other communications may take place in accordance with UK law, and in particular for business purposes such as: quality control and training; processing necessary for the entering into or the performance of a contract; to prevent unauthorised use of our telecommunications systems and web sites and/or services; to ensure effective systems operation; to meet any legal obligation; in your vital interests; in order to prevent or detect crime; and for the purposes of the legitimate interests of the data controller. Please visit the following websites for further information:

## Confidentiality

From time to time we will employ agents to process your information on our behalf. We may allow such agents, including providers of some of our services, access to your personal information. The same duty of confidentiality and security will apply to our agents. Should you take the decision to make a complaint about the service we have provided, we may be obliged to forward details about your complaint, including your personal information, to the Information Commissioner (who regulates data protection law in the UK) and/or the relevant ombudsman in existence at the time. You can be assured that they are similarly obliged to adhere to the Data Protection Act. If we or our business is taken over, your personal information may be passed to the new owners.

Insurance providers, intermediaries and appointed representatives pass information to the Claims Underwriting and Exchange Register, run by Insurance Database Services (IDS) and the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register, run by the Association of British Insurers (ABI), to which the police, the DVLA and DVLNI (Driver & Vehicle Licensing Agencies), as well as other insurers, have access. Some insurers also participate in Insurance Hunter, a data-sharing scheme. The aim of all of these is to help insurance providers check information provided and also prevent fraudulent claims. When we deal with your request for a quotation, if applicable, the insurance provider or any intermediary or appointed representative may search these registers and databases and any other anti-fraud registers set up by or for the insurance industry to provide such services. Under the conditions of your policy, you must tell us about any incident (such as accident or theft) which may or may not give rise to a claim. When you tell us about an incident we will pass information, relating to it, to the insurance provider, intermediary or appointed representative.

When you take out a motor insurance policy, including motorbike and van cover, your insurance cover details may also be added to the Motor Insurance Database, run by the Motor Insurers' Information Centre (MIIC). This has been set up to help identify uninsured drivers and may be searched by the Police to assist them in confirming who is insured to drive. If there is an accident the database may be used by insurers, MIIC and the Motor Insurers' Bureau as well as persons making a claim for a road traffic accident, to identify the relevant policy information.

## Credit searches - Insurance

Many insurance providers operate a credit scoring system and will carry out checks with credit reference and fraud prevention agencies. These checks may include electoral roll and credit information. Some insurance checks are registered as ‘general insurance searches’ and may be viewed by other credit or insurance companies if you apply for their services. When using our price comparison service, the insurance providers may use their credit scoring system before returning a price.  
Credit searches - Financial Products

Many providers operate a credit scoring system and will carry out checks with credit reference and fraud prevention agencies. Often the companies that we request quotes from will only do a credit check once you have decided on a particular supplier. Every application you submit for a loan or credit card may count towards your credit scoring so you may want to keep applications to a minimum to protect your credit rating.

## Credit searches - Financial Products

Many providers operate a credit scoring system and will carry out checks with credit reference and fraud prevention agencies. Often the companies that we request quotes from will only do a credit check once you have decided on a particular supplier. Every application you submit for a loan or credit card may count towards your credit scoring so you may want to keep applications to a minimum to protect your credit rating. 

## Cookies 

At Inspop.com Limited we respect your privacy and therefore we will only use ‘cookies’ where your browser enables us to do so. A cookie is a tiny piece of code, like a tag, which websites can place on your computer when you visit them, and act as a unique identifier that can be used to retrieve your records from databases, and to track your movement within the website.

We use ‘cookies’ to help you navigate through our site and to improve security. If you do not want one of our cookies on your computer, please ensure your browser is configured to block them. You can still use our site even if you block cookies.

You can find out more about how cookies work on <http://www.cookiecentral.com/>

## Law

These terms of trading are subject to English law and to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English courts. You acknowledge that by providing data to us, you consent to the processing of your data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

We reserve the right to amend or modify our Privacy and Security Statement at any time and in response to changes in applicable data protection and privacy legislation.
